Guide to the Caterpillar (Sherman Oaks, CA) Archive ca.1957-1987 MSS.010
Fales Library and Special Collections
Caterpillar Archive
circa 1957-1987
Fales Library and Special Collections
Eshleman, Clayton
Caterpillar (Sherman Oaks, CA)
MSS.010
12 Linear Feet (24 Boxes)
Caterpillar was a highly regarded avant-garde poetry magazine which was issued quarterly between 1967 and 1973. Edited by Clayton Eshleman, the magazine sought to publish and promote experimental poetry and writing produced in North America during the late 1960s. This collection consists of correspondence, announcements, notes, manuscripts, typescripts and photographs related to Caterpillar's run. Among the noteworthy contributors: Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Allen Ginsberg, Denise Levertov, Robert Kelly, Gary Snyder, Gerard Malanga, Diane Wakoski, Luis Zukofsky, Gilbert Sorrentino, Vito Acconci, Georges Bataille, Carol Berg, Robert Bly, Charles Bukowski, Robert Creeley, Leon Golub, Thomas Merton, Anais Nin, Adrienne Rich, and Nancy Spero, among others.
Provenance
The Caterpillar Archive was acquired via purchases from the editor, Clayton Eshleman in 1968, 1970, and 1972.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Historical/Biographical Note
Twenty issues of Caterpillar appeared between 1967 and 1973. It was published in New York and later in Sheman Oaks, Ca. In 1971, the magazine was anthologized by Doubleday-Anchor as: 'A Caterpillar Anthology.' Caterpillar has been regarded as one of the seminal literary magazines of its period. Containing what Hayden Carruth calls, "the best cross section we have of the Black Mountain movement from 1967 to 1971." Caterpillar's editor, Clayton Eshleman, is an established poet and also editor of the literary magazine: Sulfur.
Scope and Content Note
The Caterpillar Archive is a part of the Avant Garde Collection at the Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU libraries, housing over 170,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel. The Caterpillar Archive is a part of the Avant Garde Collection, collected at Fales Library during the 1960's and 70's by Mel Edelstein and Theodore Grieder. Though the date range of this collection includes material that predates and was written subsequently, the run of Caterpillar was from 1967-1971.
The materials were collected by Eshleman and were arranged in alphabetical order by subject/name and then chronologicaly within that subject. Oversized materials from the various series are located in an oversize box at the end of the collection.
The Caterpillar Archive is an archive comprised of all the correspondence and manuscript material that created Caterpillar's issues, such as: business records, magazine layouts, page proofs, advertisements, and rough drafts. Also included are Clayton Eshleman's personal papers including correspondence and his manuscripts written between 1958-76. Noted correspondents include: Robert Duncan, Cid Corman, Norman O. Brown, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Allen Ginsberg, Denise Levertov, Robert Kelly, Gary Snyder, Gerard Malanga, Diane Wakoski, Luis Zukofsky, Gilbert Sorrentino, Vito Acconci, Georges Bataille, Carol Berg, Robert Bly, Charles Bukowski, Robert Creeley, Leon Golub, Thomas Merton, Anais Nin, Adrienne Rich, and Nancy Spero.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
Series I: Clayton Eshleman: contains four boxes of Clayton Eshlemans personal documents, pertaining to the magazine Caterpillar. Included are his manuscripts, correspondence, and related material.
Series II: Caterpillar Correspondence: contains ten boxes of correspondence and manuscripts to Caterpillar, included are writings from: Vito Acconci, Georges Bataille, Carol Berg, Robert Bly, Charles Bukowski, Robert Creeley, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Allen Ginsberg, Leon Golub, Denise Levertov, Thomas Merton, Anais Nin, Adrienne Rich, Gary Snyder, and Nancy Spero.
Series III: Caterpillar Issues: contains eight boxes of page proofs, front/back covers, manuscript layouts, rough drafts, advertisements, and a author/artist index for Caterpillar issues 1-20.
Series IV: Caterpillar Galleys: contains one oversize box of galleys for issue's 1, 3, and 5.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading then chronologically within each subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into four subject-based series.
Missing Title
Series I: Clayton Eshleman, Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Related Material
Series II: Caterpillar Correspondence
Series III: Caterpillar Issues
Series IV: Caterpillar Galleys
Poets, American |v Correspondence.; Poetics |x Authorship.; Poets, American -- 20th century; Little magazines.; Poetry, Modern |y 20th century.; Sherman Oaks (Calif.); Announcements.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographic prints.; Notes.; Letters (correspondence); Poetry.; Sorrentino, Gilbert; Duncan, Robert, 1919-1988; Corman, Cid; Brown, Norman Oliver, 1913-; Caterpillar (Sherman Oaks, CA)
- Series I: Clayton Eshleman, correspondence, manuscripts, and related material
  - Vita, clips, awards, & grants, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diary, Jan.-Mar., n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence to Fales Library, 1968-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to A-C., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence to D-G., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to H-M., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence to N-R., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence to S., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence to T-W., undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellany, Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts: "A", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Manuscripts: "B", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Manuscripts: "C", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Manuscripts: "D", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts: "E", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts: "F", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Manuscripts: "G-J", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts: "K-N", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Manuscripts: "O-R", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Manuscripts: "S", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Manuscripts: "T-V", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Manuscripts: "W-Z", Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts: A-Z [Miscellaneous] Bloomington, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Manuscripts, Kyoto, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Manuscripts, Kyoto, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Manuscripts: A-G, 1962-[1965] (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Manuscripts: H-J, 1962-[1965] (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Manuscripts: N-P, 1962-[1965] (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Manuscripts: R-Z, 1962-[1965] (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Manuscripts, Peru, 1965-66.[not in Walks, A-K], 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Manuscripts, Peru, 1965-66.[not in Walks, L-N], 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Manuscripts, Peru, 1965-66.[not in Walks, O-Z], 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Manuscripts: Walks, Peru, 1966.[1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Manuscripts: Walks, Peru, 1966.[2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Manuscript: Adrienne Ariadne, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Manuscript: Theseus Ariadne, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Manuscript: A-Z, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Manuscript: House of Ibiki, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Manuscript: Hymn 23, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Manuscript: The Lay of Phi Delta Theta, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Manuscripts: A-M, n.d., undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Manuscripts: N-Z, n.d., undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Manuscripts: misc., n.d., undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Manuscripts: Aimesaire tr., undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Notebooks, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Printed Material: journal appearance, 1961-1983.. (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Series II: Caterpillar Correspondence
  - Correspondence from "A", undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from: Abrams, Sam; Acconci, Vito Hannibal; Adnan, Etel, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Alexander, D., undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from: Alpert, Barry;; Andrews, Bruce; Antin, David; Antin, Eleanor, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from: Armantrout, Rae; Armstrong, Michael; Aufustene, David M., undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from "B"., undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from: Banks, Russell; Bataille, Georges; Benson, Joyce, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from: BergCarol; Bertoni, Claudia; Bialy, Harvey, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence from: Blackburn, Paul 1960-61., 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from: Blackburn, Paul 1962-63., 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from: Blackburn, Paul 1964-65., 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from: Blackburn, Paul 1966-71., 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from: Blau, Herbert; Bly, Robert; Boffey, Peter, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Corespondence from: bookstores and radio stations., undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence from: Botlone, Joseph; Bowering, George;; Bowman, Geoffrey; Boyce, Joanne, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from: Bradshaw, Timothy; Brafman, Allen, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence from: Brakhage, Stan., undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence from: Brigham, Besmilr; Brillant, Alan, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence from: Bromige, David., undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence from: Brown, Harvey; Brown, Norman O. Bukowski, Charles; Butterick, George, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence from: "C"., undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence from: Carruth, Hayden., undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence from: Charters, Ann & Samuel., undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence from: Cohen, Robert Davis, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence from: Coleman, Victor., undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence from: Collins, Jess., undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from: Collom, Jack., undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence from: Cormon, Cid 1959-65., 1959-1965 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence from: Cormon, Cid 1966-67., 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence from: Cormon, Cid 1968-69., 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence from: Cormon, Cid 1970-71., 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence from: Creeley, Robert., undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence from: "D"., undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence from: Davenport, Guy., undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence from: Dawson, Fielding., undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence from: Dorn, Edward., undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence from: Duncan, Robert., undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence from: "E"., undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence from: Economou, George., undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence from: Eigner, Larry., undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence from: Enslin, Ted., undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence from: Eshleman, Mrs. Ira Clayton(Spencer)., undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence from: "F"., undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence from: Ferlinghetti, Lawrence., undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence from: Fox, Hugh., undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence from: Franks, David., undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence from: "G"., undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence from: Gardner, Donald., undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence from: Gerber, Dan., undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence from: Ginsberg, Allen., undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence from: Gioseffi, Daniela., undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence from: Golub, Leon., undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence from: Goodell, Larry., undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence from: Green, Galen., undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence from: Greenberg, Alvin., undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence from: Greene, Jonathan., undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence from: Greenwald, Richard[Haravec Magazine], undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence from: Grossinger, Richard., undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence from: Grossman, Richard., undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence from: Guedalla, Roger., undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence from: Gunn, Thom., undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence from: "H"., undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence from: Harrison, Jim., undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence from: Hedden, Mark., undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence from: Heller, Michael., undated (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence from: Hemensley, Kris., undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence from: Henkin, Bill., undated (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence from: Hirshman, Jack I. 1957-61., 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence from: Hirshman, Jack I. 1962-66., 1962-1966 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence from: Hirshman, Jack I. 1967-72., 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence from: Hirshman, Jack I. n.d., undated (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence from: Hogg, Robert., undated (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence from: Hollo, Anselm., undated (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence from: Hough, Lindy., undated (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence from: Howe, E. Dudley., undated (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence from: "I"., undated (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence from: Ignatow, David., undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence from: Irby, Kenneth., undated (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence from: "J"., undated (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence from: Jaffe, Nora., undated (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence from: Johnson, Ronald., undated (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence from: Jones, Jeanetta., undated (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence from: "K"., undated (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence from: Kallet, Marilyn; Katz, Leandro; Katz, William, undated (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence from: Kelly, Denis., undated (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Correspondence from: Kelly, Robert 1959-69., 1959-1969 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence from: Kelly, Robert 1970-73., 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence from: Kemp, Lysander., undated (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Correspondence from: Kennedy, X.J., undated (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Correspondence from: Kimberly, Nick., undated (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence from: Koch, Kenneth; Koller, Jim, undated (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence from: Kyger, Joanne., undated (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Correspondence from: "L"., undated (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Correspondence from: Lansing, Gerrit., undated (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Correspondence from: Laughlin, James., undated (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Correspondence from: Lawrence, Alfred., undated (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Correspondence from: Lawrence, Scott., undated (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Correspondence from: Lno, Cesar., undated (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Correspondence from: Levertov, Denise., undated (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Correspondence from: Logan, John., undated (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Correspondence from: "M"., undated (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Correspondence from: McClure, Michael 1968-70., 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Correspondence from: McCord, Howard;; McGarrell, Ann, undated (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Correspondence from: McGill, Mary Jane; McGirt, William[Inman, Will]; McInerney, Brian, undated (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Correspondence from: Maclow, Jackson., undated (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Correspondence from: Malanga, Gerard; Manglesdorf, Richard; Mariah, Paul, undated (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Correspondence from: Marlatt, Daphne; Marshall, Kathleen & Jack, undated (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Correspondence from: Martin, John[Black Sparrow], undated (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Correspondence from: Masterson, Daniel; Mechem, James; Mellen, Chase, undated (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Correspondence from: Meltzer, David., undated (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Correspondence from: Merton, Thomas., undated (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Correspondence from: Merwin, W.S., undated (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence from: Meyer, Tom., undated (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Correspondence from: Moritz, John., undated (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Correspondence from: Morris, Richard., undated (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence from: Moroff, Barbara; Morse, Jonathan; Mottram, Eric, undated (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Correspondence from: M Peter; Myers, Nei., undated (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Correspondence from: "N"., undated (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Correspondence from: Niedecker, Lorine., undated (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Correspondence from: Nin, Anais; Nelson, Stanley & Betty, undated (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Correspondence from: Nemerov, Howard; Novo, Salvador, undated (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Correspondence from: "O"., undated (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Correspondence from: Olson, Toby., undated (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Correspondence from: Oppen, George; Ossimov, David; Owens, Rochelle, undated (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Correspondence from: "P"., undated (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Correspondence from: Paden, Bill 1959-63., 1959-1963 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Correspondence from: Paden, Bill 1964-72., 1964-1972 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Correspondence from: Page, Bob; Page, Van Buren; Palmer, Michael, undated (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Correspondence from: Parrot, Jerry., undated (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Correspondence from: Persky, Stan; Perry, Halma; Perry, Philip, undated (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Correspondence from: Peters, Robert., undated (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Correspondence from: Peterson, Will 1962-68., 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Correspondence from: Peterson, Will 1969-72., 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Correspondence from: Phelps, Donald., undated (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Correspondence from: Phillips, Michael J. Plante, Allen, undated (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Correspondence from: Plymell, Charles; Pommy-Vega, Janine, undated (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Correspondence from: Potts, Charles; Prynne, Jeremy, undated (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Correspondence from: Quanbeck, Michael; Quartermain, Peter; Quasha, George; Quinn, Dennis, undated (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Correspondence from: "R"., undated (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Correspondence from: Randall, Meg., undated (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Correspondence from: Reed, J.D. Reinfrank, Arno; Reves, Carlos, undated (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Correspondence from: Reynolds, Timothy., undated (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Correspondence from: Rich Adrienne., undated (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Correspondence from: Robins, Corinne; Rosenberg, David, undated (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Correspondence from: Rothenberg, Jerome., undated (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Correspondence from: Rowan, Louis., undated (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Correspondence from: "S"., undated (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Correspondence from: Samperi, Frank., undated (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Correspondence from: Schneeman, Carol., undated (Box 12, Folder 149)
  - Correspondence from: Schwerner, Armand., undated (Box 12, Folder 150)
  - Correspondence from: Scientology, Church of; Seidman, Hugh; Shakely, Lauren, undated (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Correspondence from: Shannon, John., undated (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Correspondence from: Sharitz, Gregory; Sherwin, Judith, undated (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Correspondence from: Silliman, Ron; Silverton, Michael, undated (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Correspondence from: Snyder, Emile; Snyder, Gary, undated (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Correspondence from: Solt, Mary Ellen., undated (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Correspondence from: Sorrentino, Gilbert., undated (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Correspondence from: Spacks, Barry; Spero, Nancy; Stanley, George, undated (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Correspondence from: Staple, William; Stark, Brad; Stein, Charles, undated (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Correspondence from: Steven, Jean AndrStone, Sara; Summers, Elaine, undated (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Correspondence from: "T"., undated (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Correspondence from: Tarlow, Aya., undated (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Correspondence from: Tarn, Nathanie., undated (Box 13, Folder 163)
  - Correspondence from: Thayler, Carl., undated (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Correspondence from: Underkoffler, John; Utecho, Jose C., undated (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Correspondence from: "V"., undated (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Correspondence from: Vallejo Translations., undated (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Correspondence from: Valoritis, Nanos., undated (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Correspondence from: Van Newkirk, Allen; Vas Dias, Robert, undated (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Correspondence from: Ver Becke, W. Edwin., undated (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Correspondence from: "W"., undated (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Correspondence from: Wakoski, Diane, 1965-68.[see also poster box], 1965-1968 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Correspondence from: Wakoski, Diane, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Correspondence from: Wakoski, Diane, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Correspondence from: Waldman, Anne; Waldrop, Rosemarie; Walsh, Tom; Warsh, Lewis, undated (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Correspondence from: Weil, Jim; Weinstein, Norman; Whalen, Philip, undated (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Correspondence from: Whitney, John D.; Wieners, John; Wilbur, Richard, undated (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - Correspondence from: Wilkins, Sue; Williams, Charles K. Williams, Dennis; Williams, Heathcote [see poster box], undated (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - Correspondence from: Williams, Jonathan; Williams, Loring; Winslow, Peter; Witt, Harold M.; Woodward, Jeff, undated (Box 13, Folder 179)
  - Correspondence from: "Y"., undated (Box 13, Folder 180)
  - Correspondence from: Zdonek, Roy; Zimmer, Paul; Zimmerman, Howard; Zwieg, Martha, undated (Box 13, Folder 181)
  - Correspondence from: Zukofsky, Louis; Zukofsky, Celia, undated (Box 13, Folder 182)
  - Correspondence from: Unidentified, undated (Box 13, Folder 183)
  - Correspondence business: Anthology Proposals, undated (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Correspondence business: Grants, undated (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Correspondence business: Legal, undated (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Correspondence business: Little Magazines, undated (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - Correspondence business: Publishers & Printers, undated (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - Correspondence business: Clippings & Printed Matter, undated (Box 14, Folder 189)
- Series III: Caterpillar Issues
  - Composition & Announcement of Magazine.[also see oversized], undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Book list., undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Issue No.1: table of contents, cover photo., undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Issue No.1: writings, pg.1-34., undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Issue No.1: writings, pg.35-61., undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Issue No.1: writings, pg.62-140., undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Issue No.1: dummy pages., undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Issue No.1: dummy pages., undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Issue No.1: dummy pages., undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Issue No.2: Jan.1968, magazine(composition of), table of contents, rough drafts., undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Issue No.2: writings, pg.1-34., undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Issue No.2: writings, pg.41-91., undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Issue No.2: writings, pg.92-154., undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Issue No.2: front cover., undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Issue No.2: manuscript layout, pg.1-25., undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Issue No.2: manuscript layout, pg.35-65., undated (Box 15, Folder 16)